《越狱》第四季 第二十二集
Prison.Break.S04E22
天啊  什么都没有
God. Nothing. It's dead.
他们就要弄清楚了
They're figuring it out.
这是种什么样的炸药
What kind of explosives are we talking about?
自制炸药
Little home brew.
迈克说它能释放出C4塑胶炸药
Michael says it has the energy release of C4.
再试一次
Run the diagnostic again.
快试
Run it.
都是C4吗
Almost C4?
是的
This is it.
我们最后的机会  愿上帝保佑
Last chance for everybody.And we're gonna need a little luck.
要是我出了什么事
If anything happens to me...
务必让L.J.和索菲... ...
...make sure L.J. and Sofia....
明白
You got it.
-我也一样  -是的
-Same for me? -Yeah.
低头  我们开始
Yeah, put your head down, let's go.
开始
Let's go.
随着时间的流逝
You know, someday,weeks will go by. Maybe even years.
我们会淡忘这些事
It won't even cross our minds.
只要我们活下去
Yeah, all we gotta do is survive.
我们会的
We will.
我保证
Promise.
-发生什么事了  -没反应
-What happened? -Nothing.
引爆器一定失灵了
The detonator must have failed.
拖住他们  我们五分钟后到
Distract them. We'll be there in five minutes.
-我们没有时间了  -那你必须手动引爆
-No, we don't have five seconds. -Then you'll have to trigger it manually.
我有多少时间
How much time is that gonna give me?
滚出来  马上
Out. Now.
阿历克斯
Alex?
这里面什么都没有
It's wiped clean.
-不可能  -真的吗
-That's not possible.-Really?
-那它在哪  数据在哪  -我拿的时候还好好的
-Then where is it? Where is the data? -It was intact when I took it.
听着
I'll tell you what.
如果它10秒钟内没反应
It doesn't boot up in 10 seconds...
我会让你脑浆迸发
...I'm gonna splatter your skull all over these walls.
是我来主动找的你
I came to you.
我想结束这一切  我不会陷自己于不义
I want this over, I wouldn’t jeopardize that.
我不相信迈克就这么让你拿走
I don't believe that Michael just let you have it.
他没有  趁他不在时我拿的
He didn't. He left me alone in a room and I took it.
他就一点没怀疑你
And that wasn't the least bit suspicious to you?
也许吧  我
Maybe, I--
我不知道
I don't know.
你是在耍我吧
Are you lying?
杀了他
Kill the junkie.
你呼吸困难  是不是很痛
Your breathing's short? Does it hurt?
-我还好  -你好像是肺部虚脱
-I'm fine.-Like hell, you collapsed your lung.
不去医院  那跟去监狱没啥区别
No hospitals. Hospitals mean jail.
快点  快点
Come on, come on.
-你能帮他治疗吗  -要先检查检查再说
-Can you treat him?-I need a better look before I can try.
克里斯蒂娜呢
Christina?
死了
Buried.
你个废物
Ugh! You pathetic slug.
莎拉是我们的唯一筹码
Sara was the only leverage we had.
斯科菲尔德是个全才  可啥时候成蜘蛛侠了
Scofield's donned many a chapeau, but human fly?
我哪知道他会飞檐走壁
I should anticipate him scaling the building?
布饶发  给我枪
Move on Panama. Broffer, your .9.
巴格威尔  为我卖命的人
Men in my employ, Bagwell...
要履行职责
...anticipate.
尽忠职守
They cover their bases.
他们都能完成任务
They refuse to fail...
但你却一事无成
...which you seem to do with unyielding consistency.
莎拉的手机
That's gotta be Sara's phone.
我必须接
I should answer it.
将军  你不会有什么损失的
What do you got to lose, general?
喂
Hello.
谁
Who the hell is this?
是费尔南多・苏克雷吗  谢天谢地
Is this Fernando Sucre? Oh, thank you, God.
-巴格威尔
-Bagwell?
我们是一条船上的  一条船
And we're on the same team, brother. Same team.
我正处于水深火热中
The old boy's in a hell of a pickle.
迈克在哪
Where's Michael?
他妈妈抓走了他还有唐克雷蒂跟林肯
Uh, his mother snatched him and Tancredi, Linc too.
而我吃了一记闷棍
And I, personally, took a nasty beat down.
-她把他们关哪了  -我知道  但不能在电话里说
-Where does she have them? -I got an idea, I can't say on the phone.
我得小心点  朋友
I'm running scared, amigo.
冷静
Okay, cool it, you know what?
我们找到个人能帮我们  但我要找到迈克
We got somebody who can help us but I need to get ahold of Michael.
我们应该碰碰头  通通信息
We should, uh, get together and pool our resources.
72大街的公园  1小时后见
The park on 72nd Avenue. Uh, in an hour.
-好  马上到  -太好了
-Okay, I'll be there. -Excellent, perfecto.
你找到能帮忙的人了
You got someone who can help on his cause.
我相信他能引出斯科菲尔德
I'm certain he can draw out Scofield.
你相信个屁
You're certain of nothing.
但我一小时后要跟斯科菲尔德的朋友见面
Yet I do have a sit-down with Scofield's friend in an hour.
将军  你没有更好的办法了
You got no better hand, general.
跟着他去
Go with him.
如果他有古怪  打爆他的头
If he gets squirrelly,put a bullet in his brain.
你还真是稀客
You are a sight for sore eyes,my friend.
少来了
Can the reunion.
-迈克和林肯在哪  -他们处境不妙
-Where can I find Michael and Lincoln? -Apparently they're at dire straits.
你聋了吗
Are you deaf?
好着呢  刚才还听到你身上的硬币响
Unlikely, amigo, I just heard the dime drop on your sorry ass.
看到我左肩旁的人吗
From the bench over my left shoulder,the gentleman in the Wayfarers.
你脑袋还像在福克斯河一样不好使
Like in Fox River,you never thought things through.
告诉我要帮那兄弟俩的人是谁
You're gonna name the friend who said he'd show up and help out the brothers.
把莎拉的手机给我  不然我打破你的脸
No, you're gonna hand Sara's phone or I'll break your face.
说我是聋子  我看你是瞎子
You accuse me of being deaf,you're the one who's gone blind.
那家伙可是公司一流的杀手
The man's a Company operative-trained assassin.
伙计  你好啊
What's up, Jethro?
我们可不是在福克斯河了  T-Bag  走吧
We're a long way from Fox River,T-Bag. Let's go.
我拿到唐克雷蒂的电话了
Yeah, I got Tancredi's phone.
往一个号码打了很多次
There's a bunch of calls made to a single number.
应该是迈克的号
I think it's Michael's.
他有糖尿病吗  是否忘了吃药
Is he diabetic? Medication he may have missed?
不清楚  他是不是装的
I have no idea.Any chance he's faking it?
不是  瞳孔放大
No, pupils are dilated.
他需要CT透视  心电图和胸部X光
He needs a head CT stat,EKG and a chest x-ray.
可能是脑淤血或心脏病
May have bled into his brain or had a heart attack.
弗朗哥  仓库里不仅有斯科菲尔德和布鲁斯
Franco. It wasn’t just Scofield and Burrows.
还有赛尔夫
This is the team that Self had at the warehouse.
前联邦探员
Former federal agent.
赛尔夫干了些不法勾当
Yeah, Self was into something nasty.
赛尔夫  能听到吗
Agent Self, can you hear me?
弗朗哥探员  我们要把他转移
Agent Franco, we have to move him.
斯科菲尔德和布鲁斯在哪
Where are Scofield and Burrows?
我们要走了
We're going now.
等等  他的手动了  他能听见
Wait, his finger moved.He can hear me.
赛尔夫探员  你能帮助我们吗
Agent Self, can you help us?
他哪都不能去
He's not going anywhere.
迈克  计划是什么
Michael, what's the plan?
我们能相信谁
Who do we trust?
没有人
No one.
我们别无选择
We're out of options.
我们应该把它毁了
Then maybe we destroy it.
别无选择吗
Is that it?
穷途末路了吗
Is that where we're at?
如果将军决定报复应该怎么办
What if the general decides to retaliate?
即使我们给了他  他也会的
He will even if we give it to him.
我们可以把它弄碎  烧了
We can crush it, incinerate it.
扔到海里
Throw in the ocean.
-都行  -阿历克斯
-All three sound good.-Alex?
好吧
All right.
就这么决定了
Then it's decided.
喂
Hello?
你好  迈克
Hello, Michael.
凯勒曼
Kellerman.
你可真不好找啊
You're a tough man to get ahold of.
听说你死了
I heard you were dead.
那些流言言过其实了
Those rumors were greatly exaggerated.
我没有
No, I was, um...
我被与公司的对着干的一个组织救了
...freed by a group working against the Company.
你父亲成立的组织  我跟他们一起工作
The group founded by your father,I'm working with them.
我从那时起就一直跟他们工作
Now I've been working with them ever since.
可以帮我一把
Could have used a hand, Paul.
我来了
Here I am.
你拿到锡拉了吗
Do you have Scylla?
你认为呢
What do you think?
你拿到了
I think you do.
我也知道警察和联邦局的人在找你
I also know that you're wanted by the police and the feds.
现在说说将军和你母亲
Not to mention the general and your mother.
她不成问题
She won't be a problem.
今天5点钟有联合国的专员到迈阿密
There is a U.N. attaché who will be in Miami today at 5:00...
从你那里拿走锡拉
...to receive Scylla from you.
就这些吗
Is that so?
他是联合国秘书长的首席顾问
He's chief counsel to the secretary general of the United Nations.
秘书长了解锡拉项目
The secretary has been briefed on the Scylla program.
他决定承担起责任  你只要把它交出来
He's prepared to assume responsibility.All you have to do is deliver it.
我们需要摆脱将军
We need to stop the general from coming after our families.
没问题  但你要安排这次见面
Fine, but you need to make this meeting.
我为什么要相信你
Why should I trust a word coming from your mouth?
一旦交出锡拉  你们的罪行就会一笔勾消
Once Scylla is delivered,your slate is wiped clean.
你们所有人
All of you.
你会自由
You're free.
那不是答案
That's not an answer, Paul.
毫不夸张地说  我猜你知道你拿的东西
I assume you know that what you have can--
可以让世界变得更好
And this is no exaggeration.--change the world for the better.
你只需要交出它
All you have to do is deliver it.
你不用相信我  你只需要
And you don't need to trust me,just trust the people...
相信联合国的工作人员
...that worked at the United Nations.
手机没电了
Phone died.
-他还没有好转  -来  我们把他扶起来
-He's not getting any better. -Come on. Let's get him up.
-我去拿点用品  -好
-I gotta get some supplies.-Okay.
弗罗斯特探员和巴格威尔都没有音信
No word from Agent Frost or Bagwell.
那个滑头  要是他擅离职守  我活剥了他
That simpering little rat.If he's AWOL, I'll skin him alive.
他不可能搞定弗罗斯特  他可能被抓或者死了
No way he got over on Frost,he's captured. Or dead.
就是说我们暴露了
So we're exposed here.
就这么结束了吗
This is the end.
真是凄惨啊
Whimpering.
我们可以撤走等待东山再起
There's no shame in retreating to regroup, sir.
那可没那么简单
That, son, is a tremendous load.
喂
Yeah.
塔台发现林肯・布鲁斯的手机信号
Lincoln Burrows' phone.Pinged to cell tower downtown.
我们找到他的位置了
We have his location.
那你还愣着干嘛
Then what are you doing here?
是
Yeah.
好
Okay.
是凯勒曼
And that was Kellerman.
这个阿拉巴马拖车男干的好事
This Alabama trailer trash has been making good.
你投奔了克兰兹将军
You hooked up with General Krantz.
-管你什么事  光头  -将军现在在哪
-What is it to you, rug head? -Well, where is the general now?
跟你爹在一个地方  没人知道
Same place as your daddy.Location unknown.
还记得排队等饭那一天吗
Do you remember that day we were in the chow line?
在福克斯河
Fox River.
你对我的侮辱
You made that off-handed comment to me.
我相信一定带了民族色彩
I believe it had a racial bent to it.
说对了
Yeah.
还记得你脱臼的下巴吗
Do you remember your broken jaw?
现在赶快想出点事关生死的正经事
Now, just imagine what I can do to you now with something real on the line.
比如
Such as?
我们想要索菲、L.J.和帕姆・马宏安全
We want safety for Sofia, L.J.and Pam Mahone.
也就是说我们需要知道将军的位置
That means we need the general's location.
我会有什么好处
-What's in it for me?
我们把锡拉交出
If we take Scylla to the place it's supposed to be...
会有一个赦免名单
...there'll be an immunity list.
可以有你的名字
You could be on it.
我的阵营虽然稍占劣势
No, where I'm sitting,I'll be momentarily compromised.
但你们站错队营了  斯科菲尔德搞不定的
You're backing the wrong horse.Scofield cannot pull this out.
我们把他交给将军  我们一辈子就不用愁了
You help me get him to the general,we are set for life.
我没时间废话
I don't have time for this, man.
你应该抓紧时间站到赢的一方  黑鬼朋友
It's time you back the winner for once,my chocolate friend.
坐下
Sit down.
将军在哪
Now, where is the general?
能挺住吗
You holding up?
你要把锡拉交给凯勒曼吗
You're gonna give Scylla to Kellerman?
不知道  你相信他吗
I don't know. Do you trust him?
不相信
No.
自由之身听上去很美
The thought of walking free from this sounds good.
那是我们奋斗的目标
I mean, that was the goal.
迪克兰广场  5点钟  街对面
Five o'clock, Declan Plaza.It's right across town.
你想走就走吧  迈克
If you have to leave, Michael,you should.
林肯  我不会离开你的  你是我的哥哥
I'm not leaving you, Linc.You're my brother.
克里斯蒂娜可不这么想
Not according to Christina.
别听她胡说八道
Don't let her mess with your head.
也可能是事实
Oh, maybe it's true, you know.
我一直回忆小时候的事
I keep playing things over my head from our childhood--
她说什么无关紧要
It doesn't matter what she said.
不会改变什么的
It doesn't change anything.
不管你喜不喜欢  我都跟定你了
You are stuck with me whether you like it or not.
他们在哪  这里吗
So where are they? Here?
斯科菲尔德和布鲁斯藏在迈阿密吗
Scofield and Burrows are hiding here in Miami?
写下是哪条街
Okay, look,write the name of the street.
写下地址  你知道的一切
Give me the, uh--The number of the address. Anything.
赛尔夫  我们正在谈判  植物人
You're negotiating with me, Self,you vegetable?
医生说可以做CT扫描了  我们要把他带走了
Doc said the CT scan is free. We gotta take him now.
不说哪都别想去
He stays till he talks.
他比10分钟前的情况要糟  他不会说的
He's worse than he was 10 minutes ago, he won't talk.
但你可以写出来
Yeah, but you can write, can't you?
写下我要的信息  你会得到一流护理和退休金
So you give what I need and you'll get top-notch care and a pension.
不然就等着
Or you can waste away in front of us...
脑袋缩成花生吧
...until you have the brain capacity of a peanut.
你自己选择
Your choice.
去死吧
冷静  冷静  好了  好了
All right, all right, all right, come on. That's enough.
别管他了
Just leave him.
冷静  好吗  冷静
Cool it, all right? Just cool it.
-我没事  -他要做CT扫描了
-I'm good.  -He's gonna take a CT scan.
你要待在这里
You're gonna stay here.
-明白  -好吗
-Got it.  -All right?
要团结
Bring it together.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
能问两句吗
May I speak to you for a second?
我刚才
I was--
阿历克斯被抓了  是联邦探员
Alex was arrested, federal agent.
我们要把他救出来
We need to get him.
如果我们把锡拉交给凯勒曼
If we give Scylla to Kellerman...
阿历克斯就会免罪  他没事的
...Alex gets exonerated, he's fine.
他没事的
He's fine.
要把脓水抽出来  减轻压力  帮助呼吸
We need to get the fluid out, ease the pressure, help him breathe.
能握住吗
Can you hold that?
撑不了很久  但不影响赶路
That won't last long but we can go.
我来开吧
Mind if I drive?
巴格威尔  T-Bag
The general, T-Bag...
将军在哪
...where is he?
在伊拉克我看到一些肮脏行径
You know, I saw some pretty nasty behavior in Iraq.
很恶心
Disgusted me.
我背叛了指挥官  结果惹了一身麻烦
I ratted at the chain of command and it got me a whole world of trouble.
不是什么善事吧
No good deed, eh?
所以我们也要
So the fact that we are about to get busy...
干跟毁了我事业一样的事了
...with some of that same stuff that ruined my career...
我会这样做的
...the irony doesn't escape me.
你们好好想想
Hell, as long as you got your thinking cap on...
到底谁更有赢的把握
...why don't you consider who's really the one in power?
是我们
We are.
满脸憔悴  伤痕累累
Battered and bruised.
死神逼近
Staring death in the face.
居然还不见棺材不落泪
Surprising that you need more assurance that you've come to the end of the line.
锡拉不在我们手上
We don't have Scylla.
迈克
Michael...
你哥哥危在旦夕
...your brother is dying.
看他脸上的血色一点点消失
It's fascinating...
可真迷人啊
...to watch the blood drain from his face.
你认为他想看到同样的事发生在女朋友身上吗
Do you suppose that he would like to see that happen to his girlfriend?
索菲
Sofia.
要不给我锡拉  要不看着索菲被割喉
You give me Scylla or he can sit there and watch as Sofia's throat is slit.
两分钟内
In two minutes...
你的眼球会爆炸
...you're eyeballs are gonna pop out of your head.
那比死还难受啊
Now, that's worse than death.
我不能背叛
I can't betray.
我注定要
My destiny is to be...
成为一个令人敬仰的绅士
...a respected gentleman.
你个混蛋  将军在哪
Where's the general,you son of a bitch?
表可是在转哦
Clock's ticking.
鲁格迷你14  口径223  杀死纳温・巴纳及的枪上
Ruger Mini-14, .223 caliber. The gun that killed Naveen Banarjee.
有林肯・布鲁斯的指纹
We pulled Lincoln Burrows' thumbprint off the stock.
监控上看到你和布鲁斯在案发现场溜达
We have video of you outside the crime scene with Burrows.
难道不能是巧合吗
Isn't that a coincidence?
我没有见过比当・赛尔夫更丢人的事了
You know, I never thought I'd see a bigger disgrace than Don Self...
-但你瞧啊  -你不知道
-...but lo and behold. -You have no idea...
-你到底在说什么  -但我看得到
-...what you're talking about. -Yeah, I got eyes, don't I?
你以前获过勋章  但现在你却教唆谋杀他人
You had a badge and now you're abetting an assassination.
林肯没杀巴纳及
Lincoln didn't kill Banarjee.
他是被陷害的
He was set up.
谁陷害他
Well, then by whom?
公司
It was the Company.
公司  明白我的意思吗
Company, you know what I'm talking about?
他们发明了一种叫做锡拉的设备
They've developed a device that's called Scylla.
等等  我们能不能停两分钟
Wait, no, can we just stop for two seconds, please?
叫做锡拉的设备
Device called Scylla? Ha, ha.
马宏  我们现在在哪个星球
What planet are we on now, Mahone?
如果你想重见光明  把斯科菲尔德和布鲁斯交出来
If you wanna see the light of day as a free man, give us Scofield and Burrows.
你们把黑白颠倒了
You're missing what's right in front of your face.
他们兄弟俩没杀人
The brothers didn't kill anybody.
你们不是说想伸张正义吗
You say you're here because you wanna do the right thing?
那就听我说
Then listen to me.
相信我说的话
Listen to what I'm telling you.
斯科菲尔德和布鲁斯
Scofield and Burrows...
他们在哪
...where are they?
索菲
Sofia.
就算是生死决择
Granted, it is a fretful decision.
你们也考虑地够久了
But you pondered it long enough.
我在你手上
You have me.
林肯  你算什么  我只想要属于我的东西
I don't really care about you, Lincoln.I just want my property.
好吧  就当我知道它在哪  我凭什么告诉你
All right. Let's say I do know where it is,why should I tell you?
说不说你都是要杀我们
You're just gonna kill us anyway.
没错  你们兄弟俩横竖都是死
True. You and your brother are walking dead...
但如果我能在半小时内拿到锡拉
...but if I get Scylla within the next half hour...
我会放了索菲
...I'll release Sofia.
那莎拉呢
And what about Sara?
我们现在只谈索菲
We're negotiating for Sofia right now.
-我要你放了她  -迈克  那就快决定
-I want you to let her go. -And I want a decision, Michael.
放她走
Let her go!
好了
All right.
别动
Don't move.
放了索菲
Let Sofia go.
马上就放  打电话
Now. Make the call.
放她走
Just let her walk away.
是  马上
Yes, immediately.
好吧
All right.
-我们就此别过吧  -迈克  不要
-And this is where we say goodbye. -Michael, no.
-杀了他  -不要  我们走吧
-Kill him. -No. We leave.
-迈克  听她的  -杀了他
-Listen to her, Michael. -Kill him.
我只是个一无所有的
I'm just an old man.
糟老头
Who's lost everything.
迈克  你赢了
You win, Michael.
还有你  林肯
And you, Lincoln.
迈克  你赢了
You win, Michael.
你们都赢了
You both win.
这就是一场游戏  不是吗
Because it's all just a game, isn't it?
迈克  当你像我一样老时
When you get to be as old as I am,Michael...
如果你能活那么长
...should you survive so long...
你也会发现这就是一场游戏
...you, too, will see that that's exactly what all this is.
杀了他
Kill him.
听我说
Listen to me.
Just listen to me.
我冒着危险来这不是为了报复
I didn't risk everything to come down here for our revenge.
我是为了洗刷清白
I'm here to clear my name.
锡拉还在不
Do you have Scylla?
在
Yes.
那我们走吧
Then let's go.
走吧  将军
Come on, general.
从没料到见到你会如此兴奋
Never thought I'd be so happy to see you.
-告诉我  -什么
-Tell me something. -Yeah.
你确定凯勒曼可以信任吗
Are you sure we can trust Kellerman?
我们别无选择
You know the only thing I'm sure of is that he's our last option.
先生们  该走了
Gentlemen, we gotta leave.
快点  我们走
Come on. Let's go.
等等我
Wait for me.
迈克
Michael.
站住  不然我开枪了
Freeze or I'll shoot.
走  快走
Go, go.
迈克  开车
Michael, go.
再不去医院  他就撑不住了
He's not gonna make it much longer without a hospital.
等这一切结束再说
No. Not till this is done.
林肯  林肯
Linc. Linc.
给我手机
I need your phone.
给
Here.
打凯勒曼的手机
Dial Kellerman's number.
-别告诉我你临阵退缩了  -请只管打电话
-Don't tell me you're getting cold feet. -Just dial it, please.
语音信箱
It's a voice mail.
你最好说实话
You better be telling the truth.
这次你最好站在我们这边
And you better come through for us in the end.
他会的
He will.
那就好
Yeah, well....
我们比你更了解他
We know him a little bit better
than you do.
关掉手机
Make sure to turn the phone off.
克兰兹以前就这么找到我们的
It's how Krantz found us.
有人已经这么做了  快走  快走
Somebody already has.Hey, get out, get out, get out.
是  长官  明白
Yes, sir. Sir, got it.
你小时候在波多黎各玩过抢凳子的游戏吧
You ever play musical chairs in Puerto Rico when you were a kid?
-玩过  怎么了  -我们现在就这样
-I guess so. Why? -It's kind of what we got going on now.
这个机会  多少人正觊觎呢
Got one seat left,couple of folks vying for it.
斯科菲尔德和布鲁斯  把他们带过来
Scofield and Burrows, help bring them in,you go to Miami International...
-你就可以乘飞机去芝加哥  -马宏就在旁边
-...catch a flight to Chicago.-Mahone is two doors down.
只有一个机会了
Did I mention.that we got one seat left?
迈克和林肯试着扳倒公司
Michael and Lincoln are trying to bring down this thing called the Company.
斯科菲尔德和布鲁斯在哪
Where are Scofield and Burrows?
我们只在乎这个  这也是你出去的唯一办法
That's the only thing we wanna know.That's what's gonna help you out now.
我们的生活都被警察 探员
We've been screwed by every cop,every fed--
你想知道你妻子孩子会发生什么事吗
Do you want to know what's gonna happen to your wife, to your kid?
-他说到做到  -你如果不把他们带过来
-Yeah, he said it.-You're gonna know...
你就会知道生活被毁是什么滋味
...what getting screwed over feels like if you don't help us bring those two in.
放下
Drop it!
你认为还能去哪
Where do you think you're going?
转过身
Turn around.
慢慢地
Slowly.
放下枪
Drop the gun.
-快点  -迈克  当你
-Do it now. -Michael, when you were--
省省吧
Save it.
我不在乎
I don't care.
放下枪  把锡拉放地上
Drop the gun,put Scylla on the ground.
你就可以走了
And I'll let you walk out of here.
否则
If you don't...
我就杀了你
...I'll kill you.
迈克  你不会杀你妈妈的
You can't kill your mother, Michael.
你不是我妈妈
You were never my mother.
我也不是你儿子
And I'm no longer your son.
很好
Fine.
-那就开枪吧  -不要试探我
-Then pull the trigger. -Don't tempt me.
迈克  开枪吧
Pull the trigger, Michael.
为林肯报仇
Do it for Lincoln.
放下枪
Drop the gun!
你不会开枪的
You can't do it, can you?
哦
Oh, dear.
开不了了
Misfire.
这就是所谓的皮洛士胜利吧
I guess that's what they call a Pyrrhic victory.
你生是斯科菲尔德家的人
You were born a Scofield...
死却是布鲁斯家的鬼
...but you'll die a Burrows.
我们要把他和林肯送到医院
Okay, we have to get him and Lincoln to the hospital.
我把这个交给凯勒曼
I'll get this to Kellerman.
这次又得全靠你了
It's all on you again.
谢谢
Thank you.
-只管打电话
-Just make the call.
找到兄弟俩或与他们来往的任何人  打电话
Get Scofield or Burrows or whoever they're in business with. Get them.
再不打我们就去找马宏做买卖
This is your last chance before we take the deal to Mahone.
如果马宏开口  你也就不会在这了
If Mahone was talking,you wouldn't be here.
你到底怎么想的  你妻子孩子在北方
What kind of man are you? You got your woman and your baby up north.
你不想把她们接回来吗
Don't you wanna look out for them,get their back?
为了跟你坐牢的人
Give that up for guys you did time with?
而放弃老婆孩子
Something went down at Fox River?
你们都瞎了吗  看不出来他们在做大事吗
Are you blind? Don't you see they're doing something that's bigger than this?
-你比看起来蠢多了  -打还是不打
-Then you're dumber than you look.-Are you gonna make the call or not?
最后的机会
Last chance.
不打
No.
你回到监狱时  告诉狱友
When you're back in lockup,tell your celly...
你回绝了试图帮助你的探员
...how you shook your fist at the only feds who were trying to help you.
他出狱时  接着告诉你的新狱友
When he gets released,be sure to tell your next celly...
顺承下去
...and the one after that.
因为你要待25年  把这个蠢货带走
Because you're going away for 25 years.Get this idiot out of here.
不好意思
Sorry.
跟我们走  现在
Let's go. Now.
放轻松  跟我们走
Nice and easy, you're coming with us.
抱歉  我们要确定你没被跟踪
Sorry about all of that.Had to make sure you weren't followed.
这是联合国的所罗门・欧凯拉  来结束这一切
Solomon Okella, United Nations,this is the man who gets this thing done.
这是锡拉吗
Is this Scylla?
迈克
Okay, Michael.
你要相信我  我们要结束这一切
You can trust me. We're gonna do this,and get you patched up.
林肯
Lincoln.
莎拉
Sara.
马宏  苏克雷
Mahone. Sucre.
赦免  全都赦免
Exonerated. All of them.
放松
It's okay.
别紧张
Okay.
出错了  少了件东西
Something's wrong.There's a piece missing.
你到底在做什么
What are you doing?
联合国的人怎么能赦免我们
How is someone from the U.N.supposed to get us exonerated here?
-你在浪费时间  我们处境危险  -到底怎么了
-You are wasting time. We're in danger. -What is going on here?
要弄清楚他跟政府里的什么人联系
Need to know who his contacts are in the government.
我告诉过所有人你是个天才  别犯傻
Been telling everybody what a genius you are, don't get stupid.
我可没耐心等  他要么有缺的部分  要么没有
I'm not waiting.He either has it or he doesn't.
迈克
Michael.
如果你有的话  请拿出来
If you have it, please give it to me.
我们就可以结束一切
And we can be done with all of this, finally.
如果你没有的话  没关系
And if you don't, fine.
告诉我们  我们可以抓紧时间逃跑了
But just tell me so we can hurry up and run for our lives.
我不想再逃跑了
I don't wanna run anymore.
我也不想
Neither do I.
我会打电话的
I'll make the call.
你成功了
You did it.
一切都结束了
It's over.
举起手来
Hands up!
乔纳森・克兰兹
Jonathan Krantz?
是乔纳森・克兰兹将军
General Jonathan Krantz.
请把手放到背后
Just put your hands behind your back...
长官
...sir.
目标达到
Okay, we got everything we need.
任务完成
We're done here.
只有这个
Ahem, and this is it?
还会有些面谈
There'll be some follow-up interviews...
但就只有这些
...but this is it.
签了
Sign it...
你们就自由了
...and you're free to go.
这笔我能留个纪念吗
Can I keep the pen?
当然可以
Sure.
阿历克斯
Alex.
找到帕姆了  她很安全
Pam's been located. She's safe.
布鲁斯先生  索菲和LJ也安全了
Mr. Burrows, Sofia and L.J.are safe as well.
他们在巴拿马的警局
Police station in Panama.
最后一件事
Now, last bit of business. Um....
巴格威尔  T-Bag
Bagwell, T-Bag.
说他帮忙找到了锡拉
Claims he helped find Scylla.
在迈阿密帮了忙  也想被赦免
He was helpful here in Miami,wants exoneration as well.
我可以帮他赦免
I can make that happen.
由你们决定
I'll leave it up to you.
要以仁慈的心肠
And be kind to one another.Tenderhearted.
原谅彼此的过错  正如上帝原谅了你们
Forgiving each other just as God in Christ forgave you.
以弗所书4：32  让我们原谅彼此  林肯  迈克
Ephesians 4:32, let's forgive each other,Lincoln, Michael.
以上帝之名  我们承受了太多苦难
In God's name because there's too much pain.
我们心存太多仇恨
There's too much hate in our hearts.
我们投了一票  你很幸运
We took a vote. You're in luck.
幸运的一天
Oh, lucky day.
我们投票决定的是
What we voted on...
你在去监狱的车上能不能
..was whether or not you took a stick of gum on the van ride back...
嚼口香糖
...to prison.
你们俩不得好死
You rot in hell, both of you!
你们没抛弃我  告诉我
You don't abandon me,you hear? No....
我想告诉你  我会是个好爸爸
I want you to know I'm totally gonna be a hands-on dad.
好吧
Okay.
比如孩子如果在大半夜要奶瓶
Like if the baby needs a bottle in the middle of the night...
我会在你回来前替你暖床
...I will totally keep your side of the bed warm until you get back.
他们什么时候会走路
When do they start walking?
一岁吧
A year?
最好买些少儿读物
Better get some baby books.
我要成为芝加哥最博学的爸爸
Because I plan on being the most over-informed dad in Chicago.
那肯定了
No kidding.
我现在很幸福
I'm happy right now.
我也是
So am I.
谢谢
Thanks.
我爱你
I love you.
我也爱你
I love you too.
四年后
生日快乐
帕姆・拉尔森收
你几点走
When do you leave?
8点
Eight o'clock.
我会想你的
Gonna miss you.
我很快就回来
I'll be back soon.
MJ决定了吗
Did L.J. make any decision?
我替他决定了  参加期末考试
I made it for him,told him to take his finals.
-明年的  -是的
-Next year. -Yeah.
总推到明年
Always next year.
-好了  亲爱的  我爱你  -再见  林肯
-All right, sweetheart. Love you. -Okay. Bye, Lincoln.
-平安回家  -我会的
-Get home safe. -I will.
爸爸两天就回来  好吗
Daddy's gonna come back in two days, okay?
-见到你很高兴  -我也是
-It's been a pleasure meeting you. -Pleasure meeting you as well.
你跟华盛顿的那些坏人斗争
You fight those bastards in Washington.
-别让他们得逞  -我会的
-Don't let them give you any guff. -You know what? I'm not gonna.
-谢谢  -谢谢你
-Thank you. -No, thank you.
好的  谢谢
All right, thank you.
还记得我吗  保罗
Remember me, Paul?
我是丹尼・霍尔的遗孀
I'm Danny Hale's widow.
还记得丹尼吗
Remember Danny?
当然  艾莉森  丹尼是位真正的美国英雄
Of course, Allison,Danny was a true American hero.
把她拉走
Get her out of here. Look, get back.
没关系  没关系
It's okay. It's okay.
那个女人是谁
Who was that woman?
准备好了吗
Are you ready, my son?
愿主宽恕
打破消极的禁锢
The captivity of negativity.
就这样
It's what it is.
-就这样  -那是什么
-It's what it is. -What's that?
我拿到的一本书而已
It's just this book I got.
我不想再看到这本书
I don't ever wanna see this book again.
听到了吗
You hear?
是的  老大
Yes, sir.
要那些
Those right there.
好的  谢谢
Perfect. Thank you so much.
迈克  我们要走了
Michael, we gotta go.
看看怎么样
What do we have here?
你真酷
Oh, you're so tough, huh?
[西班牙语]
给你
Here we go.
走吧  我们去看爸爸  给我手
Come on, let's go see your daddy. Give me your hands.
谢谢  先生
And thank you very much, sir.
你想跳着走吗
You wanna do a skip?
好的  咱们走
All right, let's go.
跳着走
Let's skip down.
数到三  跳  一  二  三
And on three, biggest jump you got. One, two, three.
不是二  是三
Not two, on three.
小伙计
Hey, buddy.
哦 天呢
Oh, my goodness.
还好吗  一切都好吧
How you doing? You good?